LAC0015
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
David Brombart collection
1843-2013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
LAC0015
0.5 Linear Feet
This collection consists of materials collected by David Brombart. The collection includes both his personal files and research he collected throughout his life.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains material related to union directors and presidents dating from 1922 to 2013. It includes correspondence, autographed clippings, photographs, internet research, a report on union conflicts written by Brombart, and memorial pamphlets related to prominent union figures.
Brombart biographical note
David Brombart was born in 1933 in Belgium. He served as Youth Secretary to the Parti Socialiste Belge from 1954-1958 and was Labor Secretary to the World Assembly of Youth in Paris and Brussels from 1958-1964. From 1964-1979, Brombart was the assistant to the Executive Director of the AFL-CIO African American Labor Center in New York. During his time at that position (1975-1977), he also was a member of the United States delegation to the International Labor Organization. From 1979-1983, Brombart was AFL-CIO Deputy Director for international cooperation in London followed by a position as a senior staff member at the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions in Brussels from 1983-1986. Brombart was Deputy and Acting Executive Director at the AFL-CIO African American Labor Center in Washington, D.C. from 1986-1997, and from 1997-2005, he was a senior fellow at the Institute of International Studies in Washington, D.C.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of David Brombart, 2016 (2016.042)
General
- Letter from Samuel Gompers to Geo. P. Hambrecht, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters from William Green, 1925-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Philip Murray to Carleton Lloyd, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from John Lewis to Walter B. Leis, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters from Jay Lovestone to David Brombart, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from George Meany to Patty A. Sheffield, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Ray Marshall to David Brombart, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from Albert Shanker to David Brombart, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from Lane Kirkland to David Brombart, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence between John Vanderveken and David Brombart, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Memorandum from American Embassy Accra to Department of State, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Signed Reader's Digest article on George Meany, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Signed clippings of John L. Lewis, Walter P. Reuther, and George Meany, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Signed envelopes, 1950-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Tom Kahn memorial pamphlet, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Albert Shanker memorial program, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Kirkland Honored" clipping, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- John L. Lewis photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Conference photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  General
  Poster on speaker's podium reads "South Africa: Black Workers Need Your Solidarity"
- "Conflicts in Trade Unions" report by David Brombart, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Internet research, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- David Brombart Manuscripts Information, 1975-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Memorandum, AFL-CIO Requesting Congressional Termination of Funds to UNDP by David Brombart, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Statement to the World Conference in Solidary with the People and Workers of the State of Kuwait by John Joyce, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stephen Yokich AFL-CIO Resignation Letter, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Labor Leader Obituaries: Ahmed Tlili, Murray Seeger, and William Doherty, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles about the CIA and Drugs, Labor, and Wiretapping, 1957-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Articles about International Free Trade, 1965-2009 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Ramparts Magazein, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Nation Magazine, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- National Review Magazine, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Counter-Spy Magazine, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- AIA Journal, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Foreign Intelligence Literary Scene Newsletter, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- UAW Washington Report, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Arbeitsgmeinscaft, Checkpoint Charlie Museum Pamphlet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1843-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO Free Trade Institute Reports, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Foreign Political Aid: The German Political Foundations and their US Counterparts by Michael Pinto-Duschinsky, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Roles de Syndicats Africains Face a l'Action Medicale et Sociale, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- African American Labor Center Study by Karl Butler, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- African American Labor Center Report on 1984 Activities, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- International Communist Organizations Report, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Workers' World Magazines, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Counter Spy Magazines, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- AFL-CIO Forum Journal, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Covert Action Information Bullet, 1978-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Events and Campaigns Information, 1975-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Trade Union Africa, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Le Rire Magazine, 1918-1922 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Giving Birth to Freedom Booklet, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- African American Labor Center AFL-CIO Publication Drafts, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Africa's Trade Union Press, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Les Syndicats aux Etats-Unis, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- The Labor Redivivus by A.H. Raskin, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- The Africa Report 40th Anniversary Magazine, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- After the Dominoes Fell by Karl Gershman, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Albert Shanker Memorail, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Strengthen Trade Union Sanctions Against Apartheid, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- International Communist Organizations Publication, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Images of Labor, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Whose Freedom? Book, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- TIME Magazine on South Africa, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- The Vietnamese Confederation of Labor Speaks to the World, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- A History of the New York State AFL-CIO, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Unita: Identity of a Free Angola, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Preparing for Martial Law by Ryszard Kuklinski, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Flashes from Trade Unions, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Times: The Voices of the People, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- L'Oeuvre Newspaper, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous Art and Posters, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
- The International Labor Organization and Politics by A.M. Said Salama, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Nationalism- Part of the Solution by Nadia Diuk ands Adrian Karantnycky, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Labor and the Holocaust by Gail Malmgreen, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Trade Unions and the ILO, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Crisis in the ILO by Carlos Vela, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- The End of Ideology in Africa by Arnold Beichman, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Vierteljahres berichte, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- A Muckracker's Guide to 1968, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Political Affairs Magazine, Marxist Thought Focus, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Unions in the Yard Book, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Notes & Etudes de l'institute de Criminologie de Paris, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Berlin by Rainer Hildebrandt, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- La Politique Americaine en Afrique, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Histoire du Part Socialiste Belge, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- The Staff Union of the International, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Commonweal Magazine, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 51)